The question “What do elephants and fish have in common?” may sound strange, but researchers have found that they both have a feature not observed in any other creature.
“大象和鱼有什么共同点？”这个问题听起来可能有些奇怪，但研究人员发现，它们都具有一种在其他任何生物身上都未曾观察到的特征。
A team at the Georgia Institute of Technology has discovered that elephants use a special form of air suction in their trunks to pick up food and handle delicate objects.
佐治亚理工学院的一个团队发现，大象会利用鼻子里一种特殊形式的空气吸力来拿取食物、处理易碎的物品。
Animals using suction to handle objects are typically found in water.
利用吸力拿取物体的动物通常生活在水中。
Many fish perform suction feeding, which requires specialised body parts to quickly generate low pressure that can draw nearby food into their mouths.
许多鱼采用吸入式摄食，这需要靠专门的身体部位迅速产生低压，从而把附近的食物吸进嘴里。
The researchers have found that an elephant can do the same thanks to its huge nostrils and lung capacity.
研究人员发现，凭借巨大的鼻孔和肺活量，大象也能做到这一点。
The radius of an elephant’s nostrils can increase by up to 30%, and the volume of air that it can push through its trunk increases by 64%.
大象鼻孔的半径最多可增大30%，它能通过鼻子推送的空气量则增加64%。
This allows it to take in air at 30 times the speed of a human sneeze, enabling it to drink 3L of water a second.
这使大象吸气的速度能达到人打喷嚏时的30倍，从而每秒能喝下3升水。
In an experiment at Atlanta zoo, the researchers looked at how an elephant would pick up a small crispy pancake, which was only 0.5mm thick.
在亚特兰大动物园的一次实验中，研究人员观察了一头大象会如何拿起一块小小的酥脆薄饼，这块薄饼只有0.5毫米厚。
The force required to break the pancake was less than 1% of the trunk’s weight (about 100kg).
弄碎这块薄饼所需的力还不到象鼻重量（约100千克）的1%。
The elephant was found to either use suction at a fixed distance from the pancake to “raise” the object in the air and hold it, or gently press the tip of its trunk against the pancake and apply suction to pick it up.
研究发现，这头大象要么在与薄饼保持固定距离的位置施加吸力，把它“提”到空中并吸住不放，要么把鼻尖轻轻压在薄饼上，再施加吸力把它拿起来。
At no time during the experiment did the elephant break the pancake.
在整个实验过程中，这头大象一次也没有弄碎过薄饼。
The researchers believe that the findings could help technology companies develop better machines that use air to do their jobs, as suction has long been used in robotics to grab objects.
研究人员认为，这些发现可能有助于科技公司研发出靠空气工作、性能更好的机器，因为机器人技术领域早就在用吸力抓取物体了。
The fascinating part of the study for robotics is that elephants can use air suction both on land and in water.
对机器人技术来说，这项研究引人入胜的地方在于：大象在陆地上和水中都能利用空气吸力。
The researchers are so impressed that they suggest the elephant’s suction technique could help improve robotics technology.
研究人员对此印象深刻，因而提出，大象的吸力技巧可能有助于改进机器人技术。
Nature never ceases to surprise.
大自然总能给人带来惊喜。
Indeed, it is thought that over four-fifths of living species on earth remain undiscovered.
事实上，人们认为地球上超过五分之四的现存物种仍未被发现。
That is a reminder of how little we know of our planet, and a reminder that we are not the only creatures with hidden complexities.
这提醒我们，我们对自己的星球所知甚少；也提醒我们，并非只有我们这种生物才藏有不为人知的复杂之处。